Yeah.
>> Okay.
Welcome.
Uh each year we establish goals in
January
and uh typically July off early. We try
to review those, see where we're at,
make new
them. We are very very lucky tonight to
have Dr. here with us. She was our
moderator in January.
hope hopeful that she's excited to see
where we're going and what we've done
and then help us finish up what we
originally intended to do. So, thank you
so much for being here for
>> asking again. I thought, what's the
matter? Why do you guys want me to come
back? I was thrilled to come back
>> because you did a great job.
>> It has been an interesting six months
since since then. A lot of things have
happened. A lot of things have changed.
I see.
>> We'll see how that affects our goals.
So, tonight really what we're here to do
is to review the goals that we set in
January,
evaluate those, decide if we need to
make changes,
uh to improve
our ability to accomplish those. Uh I'm
really not I don't think we're here to
talk about new goals. Uh let's finish
what we've what we've established. So
with that, um, everyone's here tonight.
Counselor Moody is online. Uh, the only
one remaining is Dr.
not available tonight. So the majority,
eight, eight of the nine are here. And
of course, Mayor Collins is here, so we
thank you. Uh, I want to thank all of
your department heads who have helped us
accomplish and work on our goals. We
couldn't move the battle.
Um,
anything else? Anything else before we
get started on the actual court? Yes.
>> Just uh one thing for the documents that
are that are in front of you and and
Mark, I'm sorry I I didn't have them
electronically for Jennifer, but one the
staple document is really just what the
goals are for the last three years. So
what what you talked about goals for 26,
your priorities for 25 as well as 24 and
then the the six planning projects. And
then this other document is really just
some guiding questions for for you to
kind of go through of of your updates
and are you having challenges? Just just
things to sort of think about and talk
about as you go through goals.
>> Thanks.
Uh yes, Dr. Aldrich. Uh, council see I
think uh we should say thank you to
Jennifer and Tina for getting everything
set up.
>> I apologize.
>> Sorry I did not.
All right,
you want to take it away?
>> Absolutely. So let's I mean let's start
with with the six penny education and
public outreach and we have um letter
and Dr. Emmens as the champions for this
goal and talk about a progress update.
[laughter]
Go ahead and talk
We've had a bunch of things that have
gone on, but mayor's involved in a lot
of them, as is the county, all the
county departments. So,
>> is this a six penny?
>> Yes.
>> I've noticed the penny stickers going
on.
>> Yep.
Thank you, sir.
>> So, Mr. President, uh, Mr. Murphy, Matt
Murphy, put together this memo for me
that maybe just kind of goes through a
little bit of
where we're at, where we're going.
Hey, but he's done quite a bit of work
working on this issue and u you can see
all the different metrics that he has
here, but um they've done a series of
press releases on each of the sales tax
projects. Um each one featured the the
project and I brought the flyer that he
did too. I don't know if you guys have
all seen the flyer.
Um so he put together the flyer and then
from each of those propositions how he's
been doing u press releases and uh
educational things around those. Um, and
you can see like on Facebook we've had
211,000 views. 82,576
individual viewers looked at those. And
surprising to me was the one that got
the most views with Johnson Bull that uh
um it was more than I mean 166,000
people wanted to look at Johnson Bull
and that was 57,000 individual viewers.
The lowest was the police department.
I'm thinking most people aren't worried
too much about the police department.
They're just want to support it. Um so
maybe that was it. Instagram is maybe
something newer for us but again 16,000
views 8893
um
Johnson pool is up there on our website
uh we've had 1581 views of our website
uh Johnson pool was number one and fire
number two was the second lot I guess
and then after that nothing got more
than
what
so you did he did the brochure and then
Um, we've been collaborating with Blair
County on their outreaching campaign.
Um, I've spoken to Quantis Rotary and
Hill. I did an hourlong presentation to
those three groups over the last uh
couple of months.
They have been u
we have a uh a table coming up Monday
the 4th at the library from 5 to 7
o'clock. And that has put together like
this picture that we have of the front
of the building. We have a big picture
of that. We've got other uh uh
collateral that will bring us we have
two or three tables that we're setting
up that will help us with the u
the education intel right educating u on
the issue. So we've been working on
that. Our digital specialist starts the
11th of August and um his background is
Ben Silver. You guys know Ben or not.
His family we know his family.
>> Ben Silver. He was at West. Yeah, he's
West Edge Collective. So, we're very
excited to have him. He's a digital
class. And so, the first week he's going
to be here, we're going to work on some
videos and real to support um funding
process. So, so we're really excited
about this hire and so hopefully it will
be a positive thing, but um staff spoke
pretty hard on on this call.
In addition to that, Kathy and I met
with the folks out at Primrose. So that
was interesting. The gentleman that
helped coordinate that very very nice
man says, "Well, you know, you just
never know people remember to come to
this or not."
And I thought, "Sounds like my life. I
remember I have to buy my life." So, uh,
it was it was good. We had a lot of good
questions and a lot of support for
projects. So, I thought it was very
positive.
I I would like to say that uh at Super
Day, I did a shift with uh Dr. Aldridge
and an hourong shift with Councilman
Lelay and
>> we got there was a lot of people that
came by our desk when they had to guess
the jar of pennies.
>> How many were in there, by the way?
>> I don't know.
>> 3,000.
>> I think there were 3,000. I think it was
over 3,000.
>> It was the gal that guested it was only
like seven days off.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> But she did.
>> Yeah, it was. Yeah, it was 3,000.
>> We handed out a lot of brochures.
>> We did
>> and answered a lot of questions.
>> Like quit handing them all out.
>> I I thought we were going to run out
actually. And um whoever came up with
that idea about the jar of pennies was a
really easy way to engage with folks.
That's another thank you to Jen then
because that was people loved it and the
kids uh the kids loved it and the kids
would bring their parents over and then
that gave us a chance to talk to the
parents and hand out the brochures and
so that was fantastic. We've also had uh
Jason Sanchez and Tom Cobb have been
guest speakers for civic conversations
at the new senior center the third
Tuesday of the month and both of them
talked about their six penny projects
and taken information to those seniors
that gets about 25 to 30 each month
>> and this last week um the there was one
lady who said I just vote yes on all of
them and Tom was like we like that.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah,
>> thank
>> you. But I and I've done the after hours
Rotary and Republican women as well
presentations.
>> Great.
>> Well, I can say that I won't speak for
Dr. Renie, but a couple of times on the
campaign trail, it's just not been one
of the top
three issues people want to talk to us
about.
>> It is or it's not. It's not.
>> Oh, it's not.
>> Not one of the top three. No. Do they
not want to talk about it or they don't?
>> Not not one of their concerns right now.
No, I think they're mostly supportive
when the issues have come up.
>> Nice.
>> I think the environment we're
challenging. So, thanks for all your
help.
>> Any other any any challenges that
work for
I do want to say I think we need to get
some of those little stand up people
next that the county has because they
are dang cute.
>> We didn't get any.
>> We chose not to do it. The county was
random.
>> It was a good idea.
>> I have one in my lobby and a little
doctor's and his cutest stinking thing
ever.
It's just good job.
Anything
else?
>> I would like to thank Jennifer and Tina.
They put together a really nice board
for us that you might want to use Monday
night.
>> Matt, may you want to do that projects?
And so that you have it. Mhm.
[clears throat] Um I know you guys have
a a coffee council thing on Saturday if
you want to take it. It's it's near the
couches by Tom's desk.
>> Okay.
>> And there's also one of the standard non
support.
>> Okay.
>> Those like science project.
>> Perfect.
>> Yeah.
A lot of the projects.
>> Well, we're going to have to do the
fifth penny soon as this one's over. So
hopefully we learned some lessons from
this and u continue these same efforts.
>> That's a good thing.
>> Great.
>> These um I'm assuming these efforts will
continue after the president, correct?
>> This is the six finished on sorry
>> and then we start then you start. But if
we do get the six pay, I hope that we
will be more proactive throughout the
entire four years we're collecting it
maybe than what we have been this last
four years. Making sure that we get
stickers on everything, putting up the
sign to say this this was funded by the
six penny, you know, fraud that was
passed on in 2026 or whatever. So I
think we got a little um lax about you
know letting reminding people what six
penny was paying for
idea
>> three more weeks of course
>> from Tuesday
>> people are voting today
I
>> that's
Okay.
>> Yep. I think we're good.
>> Okay. And um Collins will stay with you.
Improve the city's public information
strategy.
>> Yeah. So, um talk a little bit about
that. You know, after this came out as a
goal, um I asked a a PR firm to do a an
analysis or audit of where we're at. And
uh I shared during the budget my friend
what what I got was that u the things
we're doing we're doing very well and I
think he called them green field or she
called them green fields my bad. So
there there are things that you do that
are designed to last for a while. And
her her say criticism or her comment was
cityr side should have more staff and uh
we should be doing non green building.
So videos things that are designed to go
for like uh 24 to 48 hours you know a
short shorter window more social media
Instagram Tik Tok those types of things.
So in this budget we put in uh for
full-time uh digital uh communication
manager um that was approved by the
council. So we've already hired that
person and their first day is August
11th. So July 1st to now we've got that
done and uh person comes from a
background of a company that does a lot
of this does this really well. So I'm
excited about that and that will allow
us to complement what Matt does and will
also free Matt up to do more of those
things. And I think on the last page of
this
as as we looking ahead um Matt shared
with some of the things that that we
want to do and that is creation of a
city newsletter for res
like the mayor's but you know just a
citywide one uh we've done awide survey
I think the last time we did it
um in fact last time we did a a citywide
survey I told him I thought maybe was 12
or 15 years ago that we did that.
>> Quite a while.
>> Yeah. So, going back out and and doing a
survey of direct find out what's still
going on in their thought processes and
and helping us and uh
and then we would really like to get a
new website, but if nothing else, we'd
like to make our what work on our
website.
And so, those are some of the things
that they have on their list uh to do.
But when we talk about um
press releases, uh we're up 31.5% in the
six months over the previous six months.
Uh you know, we talked about needing to
get more information out on things. Um
we started the civic engagement program
and we've had over 1500 participants and
2100 total clients that have come from
that. And then we've been involved in a
whole bunch of planning and development
projects. uh for that the data center
landing page uh the transit community
surveys we pest they started a new
program this June all the DD initiatives
um did surveys on 16th and on the budal
justice program 18th street
reconstruction built a landing page for
that the data center panel that we did
um so we started to do more of those
types of things to uh
using some of the tools we currently
have to
hard to meet that goal.
>> We've also implemented council corner
that should go out the next day or two.
>> Really, that's just an effort to let
folks know what we've been working with.
When I when I read that, it's like
Yeah. been doing a lot of stuff.
>> That goes over really well at council
and coffee,
>> doesn't it?
>> Yeah. And at the senior center. Um,
President Secret, I'm just wondering if
as as a new person starts in August, I
don't know if any of you
well probably a lot of you don't hang
out on social media as much as probably
I do, but um there is a lot of a lot of
really good uh posts that the library
does that are actually attracting a lot
of people to the library website and
they're just hysterically
They are. And not only that, Dr.
Michelle, but um they're they're get
making nationwide.
>> Some of their some of their posts have
gone viral nationwide.
>> They are so darn
>> they are fantastic.
>> Yeah, they're social media persons doing
amazing things. So, I would hope that we
could do something like that that would
build some goodwill and maybe not be
such a negative. I mean, we just seem to
be in this negative news cycle right
now. So, if we could do something that
would bring people to our website and to
the city site that are not that would be
um fun and lighthearted.
>> And in fact, they uh when they did the
lucha libre Oh yeah.
>> They got Commissioner Thompson and
Commissioner Mom
>> in there
and it was it was pretty hysterical.
really excited that Van is the person
that's going to do this because um I
know that Matt's experience is mainly in
print media. Uh, and Ben, I worked with
him when we re rebranded our
organization and redid our website and
all that stuff. And he's very, very good
and he's creative. And that this weekend
I was looking at what other cities do
that are relatively our size and then
what we do. And all of our stuff or the
majority of our stuff is static.
>> It's just, you know, here's the
information. But if you look at, you
know, Love One, Longmont, Fort Collins,
that's bigger, but some of the
communities around us, they've got some
really nice kind of in the line with
what the library does. not that cool.
But, you know, like each division or
program, they'll have um somebody from
there do a 30 second
thing that other you know, I could just
see all kinds of opportunities for um
Jason's group to do some really cool
things.
>> Jason's group does themselves.
>> They have their own people and those
guys do that.
>> Yeah. kind of in that vest department.
>> Yeah.
>> To do
>> I think we'll
>> Ben will do a really good job of that.
>> Yeah. That we're I'm excited about is
I've talked to them about doing
recruiting videos like for engineers and
for police officers and those hard to
hard to uh hire people that we could do
some really fun videos that we can put
out there that might make people think
this could be a fun place to work. So,
we'll work on that. The police
department did one a couple years ago
and uh it was pretty good, but I think
we can we can improve on them.
>> Somehow I'd really like to see us do a
pre and post counc. Here are the topics
we're going to talk about. Come join us
and after the meeting is over the next
day. Hey, here we talk about it. This
was the discussion
>> after the game.
>> After the game, the post postgame post.
uh this was the discussion and this is
how we arrived at this decision. I think
the people understand
how we what we had and how we got to
>> I think that helps. So when you set up a
Monday night football look what you
think you actually
>> play by play be kind of funny you know
hey what do you expect in today's game
you know
>> and maybe some review clips right? Yeah.
>> To to your point, um my my mother-in-law
lives at uh
pointful and she really appreciates the
uh mayor's minute and the council
corner. She she really feels like she's
um kept up to date on what's going on.
>> Yeah.
>> I always hear things about SP too. Y
>> but I'm wondering too if and maybe it's
part of that survey, but since we've
gotten so bloodied over I don't know
what's happening. Nobody tells me what's
going on. If part of the survey should
be how do you want your information?
>> How do you get your
>> so that we can see what we're missing? I
mean, maybe we're hitting all of it, but
just finding out, is there something
we're missing?
>> And quite honestly, I mean, it's great
that we're doing more press releases,
but I'm not sure that that's really how
most people are getting their news these
days.
>> I still get the old
>> I was going to ask about that. Um it
seems like most people either get their
news via social media which is
>> it's on our social med
page
>> and digital
>> it's on it goes on cap city news it's
covered under those things. So every one
of those cap city news covers wet book
covers
>> both on their electronic and static. I
work with two people who they were
following the Nancy Guthrie story and so
we were traveling and then I and they're
like constantly on their phones. I'm
like what are you doing? They're like uh
and you know and they're giving me all
these nancy Guthrie updates and they
said well it's in the paper. And I'm
like I didn't see anything like that in
the paper because I I still get the old
school hard copy paper and they're like
oh no no
they said Michelle and they're in their
40s. Both of these women are in their
40s. They said the paper is actually um
is uh not Twitter, the the one we're not
allowed to use for the state.
>> Tik Tok. Tik Tok. That's what they call
the paper and that's where they get all
their news and they're in their 40s. And
I was like, "Oh my god,
>> that's what I was going to ask in
looking at this. I mean, I know we're I
think we're doing a great job, but
>> they haven't utilized Tik Tok and I know
a lot of governments are very
state of Wyoming.
>> We talked about it now that you know
there's been a change in the ownership
and things. I think we probably need to
get to that area. We'll talk a bit about
that.
>> Some reals and things.
>> I can't wait to see you all in Tik Toks.
>> I've never been on TikTok.
I've never seen it.
>> Join principal and my daughter will make
fun of me if I find a joy.
My daughter, you want that younger
like $10,000 a couple years ago because
of all of her posts on TikTok.
>> Yeah. It's it's does the um does Matt
work with other organizations to make to
drop links in other organizations to
connect with the city?
wonderful because that's something that
we could do too that you know we can put
link our links on other organizations
that agree to do that
>> chamber.
>> Yeah.
>> And then they could just click into that
from that other site and get our
information.
>> State Daily is the largest
>> Yeah.
>> People were taking putting that in air
quotes. How how can we better utilize
that? I mean, they cover some of our
stories, but
>> they have a statewide focus,
>> right?
>> I know, but
we need to we need to be more involved
in that.
>> Controversy, they'll cover it.
>> More shootings, more
people getting gored.
>> I would assume when he does a press
release, he sends it to them, too. Maybe
they just don't cover them,
>> right? Not very exciting.
>> It's not just that state focus that I
think they're looking for, but uh
Garrett and Cy, those guys are covering
the ball for us. Now, what I found, and
I'm not very good with this stuff,
believe me, social media and that stuff,
but what I've noticed with Cap City is
something happens at 10:00 in the
morning, they've got it on their site by
noon.
>> It's a it's a
immediate update. It's not an overnight
type. Yeah,
>> which I don't think is interesting.
>> I did a long interview with them
yesterday and so I think we'll see a six
penny sales tax article
next week or so.
>> The chamber doing a six penny launch
next week.
Chamber
data center
weeks.
>> You get tickets.
Oh,
>> did anybody else get tickets to go
>> for that? I know you go.
>> Any other ideas on
my taking your here? Anything?
>> No,
>> not at all. You guys are I think you
guys are doing great.
>> Great progress. Um, one one thing to to
consider
is um Ben's that your new your new
person if he can coordinate with the
other u marketing people at places like
the chamber and the other organizations
when you when you share each other's
information and follow each other and
the more you can share it out the more
it will get shared out
if they can collaborate
>> I think you'll hear other demographics
>> more with the schools of the college you
know the younger
students in this community
>> through the talon owner.
Well,
>> is the talent are they still printing or
is it all digital now? Everything is
digital. That's what I thought.
>> Is there any way we can better
coordinate that?
>> Absolutely. I would love to see us do
something where I don't know if one of
the things I wondered about it is doing
like a focus group with the college to
talk about how do they want information
somewhere
um as a as a way to connect them with
the city but use their brain power and
maybe figure out a way to connect
better.
>> Yeah. We And so our our new position of
the chief experience officer, she she
did 84 focus groups with over 800
students this last semester. And I I
heard you say people are mad that we
don't get the information. Students have
the same the same and you know short
from us going to every single one of
them handing it to them. You know we ask
them where where do you get your
information and how do you prefer that
we communicate with you? And when that's
when we have that complete, I think we
share that with with all of you. So you
can at least see where the college age
students are saying this is how and it's
not Tik Tok. It's um know it's we want
one place we can go to which is great.
We have places on the website but then
how do you get them to go there?
>> Like a dashboard. So the well even the
website so QR code that takes me here
>> or a a this is where I go to get my
information and so we you know we've
created some things not so much a
dashboard but a
>> at at the college canvas this is how you
go on your online classes this is where
you go to get your grades this is where
they look for things more than anything
so we put the information there to where
they go to the most common places
>> is where's a top of mind where do I
what's the first thing I look at when I
do that
>> and we actually may have to pay for some
advertising as a city because I don't
think we put very much aside for
marketing
>> because the algorithms for Facebook I
guarantee my Facebook page is different
than yours
it's exactly the same as Pete's though
but it but just depending on I'm jo I'm
making a joke
but Facebook you know where you go and
what you do
>> see we follow the same things.
>> See, is there any way that I'm again I'm
anonymous
somehow use your eyes on the plaza to
get out QR codes access.
Hey,
>> while you're sitting there waiting for
the musicians to this is the latest hot
topic, you know, scan it, tell us what
you find. Yeah.
>> Yeah. We could have QR codes set up and
they stay while they're sitting.
>> Everybody's got a phone. Everybody's
using those and you know, ask no more
than three questions and you'll get
answers.
>> One other question. How about the school
district of school district one? Do they
have a publication or anything?
>> Um,
Mary Qu, their communications person and
they were doing it uh they were doing it
quarterly. They've cut back on how often
they're doing their old newspaper, but
um they still can put out stuff. They
>> are
>> they don't like to
>> I don't want to say share, but because
they're trying to get people focused on
their things. We had worked with them to
try to
>> because of them. Yeah.
>> Yeah. To try to get our stuff out there
and they were like, well, we want them
to pay attention to ours. It worked
great during co but just as a general
trying to drive them to cartridge to the
11.
>> But you can buy an ad in their magazine
a
>> good
encourage them to check the city
>> site. QR codes are
and young people use QR codes all the
time. Yeah, it's true for every venues.
>> I hate when I go to restaurant, they
have
>> give me a paper menu.
>> Half the time I run my glasses, I can't
read that. I
>> try reading it on your phone. I heard
you are getting harder.
>> Okay.
Wow.
you know on the ground.
Okay. Uh previous projects and and
goals.
So I'm I'm not sure if you actually want
to go through all the previous projects
and goals. I think we've really talked
about a tracking system. So I'm I'm
interested if we've done anything on
that on how to track the previous goals.
>> If we have I'm not aware of it. Um had a
conversation with the engineer's office
early to try to figure out um how did
they feel about a project management
system and where they were at with that
and that
>> we didn't really know anywhere. Um, so
that's about as far as
>> Oh, I had great I had a great lunch with
a young he lady does this with her job
and uh I think there's a lot of
potential looks to me like there's a lot
of u lot of energy it takes to get it up
and running and right now bandwidth is
our challenge but I think it's a great
idea.
It's so great to have a site that we
department heads whoever wherever we
allow it go to that site and have it
updated you know where are we with
project X
what's the last entry where you know but
then of course it has to be updated
>> that has to be updated has to be managed
and created
>> can you see that with open dove do they
have a dash with open
mayor
>> well I think eventually we'll get there
but we're not
>> we're not we're still working trying to
see if it's worth the way we want to
>> connect Cheyenne isn't the
main projects we're doing is see
>> I don't know
>> the revenue
>> that's
people have been keeping that
up to date pretty much so much of those
things you know
there are milestones and then there are
things going on in the background that
none of us are really aware of unless
you go find out.
Uh and and we don't want we don't want
project management software up there. I
mean, you know, there are city engineer
and other people use that all the time,
but it's it's got more detail than we
want.
>> I think that
dashboard that we would have publicly
behind stuff would be how to bring
people plan
number.
>> No. Well, it's a bandwidth right now.
>> Yeah.
>> I'd be I'd be curious if we can look at
other communities to see how they
structure their
>> Yeah. Just saying
>> information technology that helps.
>> So, the the 2024 priorities, there's a
website for a majority of those
projects. there's at least a link that
takes you to a a web page that gives you
an update of of all those and and
they're actually you know if there's I
mean the one on the pump house was
pretty current
um as current as February 2026. So some
some who's up
>> was it a cut on fire? That's what it
said. [laughter]
>> That was March.
>> No, it was approved an agreement for
design work to restore the historic
>> Oh, yeah. But you know,
>> but that's not my point. My point is
there there was a a a web page for each
one of those priorities. If you wanted
to go and find it, you could go and, you
know, if you wanted to see an update,
you could go to that page and and there
was, you know, there was an update on
them. I don't see any of that for the
2025 goals or the 2026 goals, but I I
don't know who who created those or who
was managing those.
>> Matt did that.
>> Matt did that. Yeah.
>> So, Matt does the next Cheyenne and
Charles does that. Um that's it's kind
of a joint project between two of them.
>> And Mayor Collins um you said Band did
that include human personnel as well.
I'm assuming
>> that's all we're talking about. Yeah.
>> There's a lot of projects up on that
connect Cheyenne website.
>> Yep. There's a lot
steps.
So maybe we just need to do a better job
of driving for that.
>> July 26.
>> Yeah, I I think there's a lot is
actually going on. You may have to sort
of search around more, but clearly we're
getting a lot of information.
>> So, and driving that
>> right. Exactly. Driving that to the to
that one place.
>> So, so people know what's happening
because there there is there's a lot of
projects here and a lot of things
happening.
Done. Done and done. Okay, great. Good
job everybody.
>> Want to talk about any specific
projects?
>> I would like to give a little update on
our revenue thing that we Hen and Kathy
and I have been trying to work on. Um,
so I we one of the things we had worked
on was reviewing city- owned real
property. One of the properties that we
identified that could be put up for sale
that we don't currently have a use for
is a house out on Christensen Road that
was purchased when the Christensen Road
overpass was done. And it was used um by
city offices temporarily, but it's been
empty now for the last
green plus years was quite a while it's
been empty that um some of the flowers
during co right so yeah I think it's
been longer
>> so six years but uh unfortunately it was
vandalized um pretty heavily this last
winter and a lot of damage was done to
it the doors were destroyed and um
>> yeah so Doug Kon took it upon himself to
work with um
his crews and they've been trying to get
it ready to put on the market. And so um
checked in with TJ yesterday. He was
waiting to hear back from Doug, but he
thinks it's pretty close to being able
to be released to be able to put out for
bid. So, we actually had people calling
because it had uh been
uh it had not been put out for bid, but
people knew that it was getting ready to
be put out for bid and they had been
calling the office uh his to find out
when it was going to go up for bid. And
so, um I think there are people out
there that are interested in purchasing
it or bidding on it, but we have to get
it on the market first and we needed to
do that those maintenance things. there
had been proof of um some favor and some
things that left bags and bags of
clothes and couches have been moved in
and all sorts of things. So anyway, I
think that it's going to be we can
hopefully get that out for bid soon so
that we can not have to worry about
maintaining that or taking care of
vandalism. Um, we did collect all of the
uh, leases from each of the city
departments that they currently have and
we've also collected all of the fees for
all of the services that the city has.
And that's kind of where we're at. So,
anything that I forgot?
So, anything that I forgot, Kimmy?
>> Probably the properties that uh, certain
neighborhoods have that are behind their
houses.
>> Oh, yeah. We did. And I had talked to
the mayor about that and they actually
did talk about that at summer wham. Um
>> it's going to be on our legislative uh
thing to see if we can find a uh a
sponsor. The hard part is you have these
like 2 foot by 12t in somebody's
backyard.
You know, nobody else is going to buy
it. You don't want any of us to buy it
and go into somebody's backyard. But how
do we dispose of those without the state
process? So like a dimminimous property
giving us a way to go through that. We
just did one recently where there was a
conflict and we just did a lease with
them. Uh so they'll maintain it, take
care of it and we leased it to them. So
that took care of the conflict, but um
you know that's going to be difficult to
continue to do. So we're going to ask
the legislature to give us a path
forward minimum property so we can just
go to that property owner and we won't
make a lot of money on but we'll just
get them off our books. We don't have to
be responsible for insurance,
maintenance, you know, that kind of
stuff. Just get rid of them. And at WHAM
when I was talking with some other
communities um every single community
across the state has the same issue that
the state process is just not uh user
friendly and getting rid of these small
pieces of property. So So hopefully once
after the election they'll go a find a
person that's reasonable and sponsor it.
There'll be many.
Well, I think one of the things I mean
we really haven't talked about the
things that we actually should celebrate
u you know Reed Avenue the work that's
been done on that Pete member Tom
this morning uh I mean there
you know the appropriation we did work
with mayor you've been doing with the
rare I have an update on both readout 15
street if you want to Yes,
>> Mr. President. That's okay.
>> Thank you. Which one?
>> I have my
reason the press. I I picked things up
just as I was coming to the meeting.
Um maybe we could start if you don't
mind on Reed Avenue. Only reason I can
say that is I've been more with all that
five instances we've been talking about
is I did with
representatives from the BNSF and it was
I think a very refreshing meeting. Um
there was I think three people in the
property and construction office that
were there including the the LFA
gentleman that is in charge of that and
their government affairs person and the
whole meeting was not about you know is
this a project we're going to do it was
coordinating the last details to do the
project so you know talking to us about
our FRA grant making sure what can they
do to support that as we move forward
with the FA they'd like to be able to
part of that. Um they they were talking
about um you know timing. They were
talking about u basically um as soon as
we can get this to them so they can
finish their uh their review of it. Um
you know what that timeline would look
like. Um so it was the most refreshing
meeting I've had to the railroad in my
securities as mayor. They uh they are
committed to the project. They I think
it's a big project. They want to be part
of it. So, but this gives you a little
bit of the timeline and and the things
that are going on. But, um, I think
we're we're getting close to that 60% if
I remember correctly. Um,
>> that's what Tom said at the CD center
last week.
>> Yeah, I think I think we're getting
close to that 60% design and uh would
ask them give that a quick look and make
sure that that's going to be February.
That's what it said. But, I think we're
getting close to that now. And um and
then over there we've got an appraisal
going on. You know, part of this was we
have to uh we have to pay down get back
our right away. And uh the good part is
it's a onetime payment and then it's
good it's good forever. And so basically
10% of the price value. You talk about
the script lot of whatever that is. It's
not going to be as as they said. And so
that appraisation is ongoing and and
that that efforts on.
So eventually we're going to write them
a check. They're going to uh they're
going to give us a uh an agreement. FRA
is going to write us a check. We're
going to close for
intersection 17th, 18th, 21st in Diller.
Did I get that right? I did that. And uh
and then we're going to be able to build
on the eastern side, which kind of
changed the half a little. Can't build
both sides, but we'll be able to build
eastern side. and um 17 we have a
quarter actually happen. So I think in
the next couple of years probably
>> a quarter of a million dollars is worth
you're thinking is going to be maybe 10%
of the value.
>> I think that's the insurance I have no
clue as to what that might be.
>> When is the appraisal expected to be
back? Don't know. I honestly don't know.
You got to get the appraiser that the
railroad ride and those kind of things.
So I I don't know that that that's
I know that they're they're they're
working out all these things. J McDonald
and uh DH is that DHM
>> DHM
>> DHM and uh
Fell they're doing a really good job
right now
pushing hard to get 60% so we can get
that in the process. We'll see. I feel I
feel like we're finally I feel like
finally for the first time this project
is actually going to happen. I would not
have given me their odds before two
years ago I would have said I don't
think it's going to happen. So I think
this is happening.
Well, I think fair, you know, just in
the six months I've been on here and
dumped into a big project right when I I
was appointed come a long ways
and then you got people who have
business there are excited about it
businesses changing hands. I don't know
how many of you run into Tony Bero from
the uh ANC.
Uh next time you see him, ask him to
show you the renderings that he's got
for his building that he asked AI to uh
do that's really phenomenal to see you
know what kinds of plans
and looking at and Sharon he wants to
settle the place but uh so a lot of
really positive things there. Do you do
you know may bear have they designed the
road crossings and what those are going
to look like or is that early agency
just I don't know if it's did they tell
you I don't think they're I think that's
part of what I'm working on
>> I think that's uh
>> that's part of
>> here we have the uh
contract mod uh
the additional scope and services
coming. I've got a August 10th date
here. So basically um that would be
which I think is the most important
immediate issue
is close the road and come up with uh
some way to do that design it. And uh so
I expect
we're going to have a big contract mod
coming. I Tom was talking about
lighting on those guys and saying get it
to me and uh I think it's going to be
essential we pull the trigger and
proceed. Um I think we should sell
naming rights on our closure.
Go to West.
>> Everyone else has naming when we uh Tom
presented this at the senior center last
week and he talked about those four
streets closing that there was not one
person there that had any
any reaction to those traffic numbers.
there are 120 cars a day or the numbers
are so small. I was actually surprised
at how few cars actually go through that
intersection. I was I was really
shocked. The other thing that I'm going
to ask this governing body to do is um I
would like to make that whole section a
quiet zone.
>> Quiet zone. We're doing some things to
kind of screw with their quality of life
getting in and out of the neighborhood.
And right now when the railroad goes up
there, they they lay on that whistle um
the whole way. And um we can create a
quiet zone where they can go through
without having to do that. Which means
with the streets that are open uh we'll
have to have some uh maybe a little bit
um different farms, you know, warning
signals, but then that that neighborhood
won't get woke up in the middle of the
night by train. And so they're they're
thinking that might cost $150,000,
$125,000 to make that a flight zone. And
I told them we should go ahead and
design that. Um because I was pretty
sure governing body would want to help
that neighborhood out. Um, there's
nothing worse than you're laying in bed
at one o'clock in the morning and get
startled awake by a a train. That would
just take me off of it. So, I mean,
they're they're going to look at what
that would take,
>> right?
>> Uh, BNSF is good with it and apparently
FNSF
won't do it, but they'll support it. So
we talked about that very
>> that's one of the issues that has come
up with people that I've been visiting
with on campaign is that
uh I said do you hear more noise from
the railroad or the data centers
>> railroad
and also I said you know when I
graduated high school I would have had
the choice go and work for Microsoft
go and work for Union Pacific
I would chose Mikey Health.
>> You'll never die. It would have been
easier on your baby
>> and I probably wouldn't have asthma.
>> But you wouldn't get to go to North Plus
>> and then I would have lost all my
>> all my good oneliners
Nebraska.
>> You know when the stenciling departments
are going to be like they told me
they're pre-leasasing them. So that
means they're getting close. I've not
talked to neat lately. I' I've been
digging to call.
>> Yeah. The railroad. Well, here
>> they fill all that up. They get the
whole If the trains aren't quiet,
they're going to fill that.
>> No problem.
>> Yeah, I think so, too. And a market
ready.
>> Are you guys Are you guys okay with the
idea of doing a quiet film though?
>> Absolutely.
>> I told them I didn't think there'd be
any questions.
>> Do we have to wait till after?
>> No, they're they're worth they're
they're going to do
they're going to do the race. I did. Did
I think you met with me Kaplan last week
also, right? I met with that made for
lunch with
>> who else met?
>> I did.
>> I did not.
>> U
>> he said that it's been he he was I mean
he seemed to think that we've made a lot
of progress with the railroad and this
process and that we stand a really good
chance to get the funding.
He sent from
>> Oh yeah, that's everybody's inside this
one.
>> He sent a email this week with a whole
bunch of different grants to swipe
forward.
>> Oh, great.
>> You should send us.
>> He also I didn't realize that he has
some I had just last week had somebody
contact me about how bad the rail the
bridge looks over East Lincoln Way,
>> right? um and it needs to be painted and
taken care of. And so I gave that to him
and he said that on their board they
have the president of each of the major
railroads that make up the gold rail
organization and that he would take it
to them and um let them know that we
need to get that taken care of.
>> Was that the one that was painted like a
flag?
>> No, I think it's just rusted really
badly and the paint's peeling. sent us a
mail and ideas for how to paint those.
>> Oh, yeah. I don't know that we're going
to get down that way, but I think that
they'll at least take care of the rest
of the paint, the basic paint. So,
>> should we go to 15th?
>> Go to 15th.
>> We have real
progress.
So, I thought our young man uh Mr. will
do a nice job on her car.
>> I will say um even folks that may not
have been initially supportive of the
project, the ones that have seen those
cars are astounded at the workmanship
that took place.
>> Did a nice job. I did. The one green one
is definely
just
>> see it's historic.
>> And all last week there was always
people over there looking at them. Yeah,
I saw that.
>> I think we get everything moved around
and I think it will look really nice.
But uh so I think the next big thing for
us is getting old Satie Green restored
and getting her on the the lodge. Uh Mr.
She and I really want to get um a bigger
a bigger locomotive down in that general
area
in front and then finishing the master
plan which is the lighting and the other
things along Wood Street or something.
So u
making progress
Mr. Mayor that's up there and has been
involved talking about old s for years.
We just need to do a bit of uh
communications with the folks at the
Mormon Heights area uh about what that
timing of that is and the reasons for
it. Um I've certainly come around
believing that that's uh something that
we ought to do and the plans works for a
long time. Um and it's just a matter of
telling people what the facts are. what
the vendor
>> I think the people that have also made
don made the donations and purchased
those city and handy word has been
working for that list at the botanic
garden so that those people could if
they're sold I mean could be sent I mean
some of them are probably dead um but
they could be sent some sort of a email
or I mean a letter saying this is what's
going on why because I think I think
that money was collected for sadi with
it
with the premise that it was going to be
at the Botanic Gardens. And so
>> I don't know
90s.
>> All All I know is she's rusting apart
right now. And I'm worried that we don't
do something pretty quick. She's going
to break in half. She's 1890
>> and she's got no love since she was put
there. And if you just leave her there
and let her r that that's that's bad.
Yeah.
>> I think we need to save her. So the idea
would be to to bring her out. Let Mr.
Pamel or somebody must order her the
best that they can and put her on
display where everybody see.
>> When I talked to him, he thought he that
she might have to be done on site.
>> Yeah.
>> Because she's so brutal and so in such
bad shape now.
>> He told he told me that can't move it
until the ground is frozen.
>> Yeah.
>> Because they got to bring they have to
bring a crane lifted
>> and this last winter ground never got
right.
>> Really crane
some covered. Yeah. said he told us that
you're more aware of the name but he has
found
>> Yes.
So the caboose
>> Yeah. I think 18 is 1880. I have a
picture of it.
>> Yeah. He wants to make part of the
old caboose.
>> It's the only one in existence.
>> It's a shed in somebody's backyard.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh. Over on the south side of town or
west side of town. Yeah.
>> You talk to them, right? and they're
willing to we'll build him a new shed
and they'll give us the old and he can
find the original truck. There's
original trucks for it available and he
really wants to do that project. So
it'll be an 1890 locomotive with a
caboose of similar vintage.
I think that would be fair. Yeah, that's
something.
>> And then the fence around city man. I
think somehow we need to incorporate
that. That that is a you know what I'm
talking about some historic fence. Oh,
is it got all this stuff welded to it?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Family put that all together. They
found it along the tracks over the years
and welded it all. It'd be a great
story. I think that's part of the story.
It needs I really believe in
>> every time you look at it, you see
something
>> at the fence.
>> There's one of the house that you use
that even
>> cool. So anyways guys, we make we made
serious progress. We we met the EDA a
requirement to $600,000 that we have
mediate. We should be able to uh to
capture those dollars towards this
project and
I think we're on on track to uh get
done.
>> Yeah, I do think the cars look
beautiful.
Y
>> we're done with that. I'd like to just
talk about the bell war real quick.
Couple of weeks, several weeks ago
through uh the mayor
with one of the
potential developments to do on-site
environ.
We have a group that built Q cells solar
on the south 85 highway few
um they're looking at three different
phases phase one would be about 1,200
acres I believe
um would be a substantial money to the
city we haven't got a final number but
somewhere somewhere around a half
million dollars a year for the lease it
would be a lease not a sale
25 your lease. So, if they could do
that, do a second phase two and a phase
three.
Pretty substantial dollars to the city.
Um,
I'm not sure when they're going to be
here to start, but they want to do it
now. I think I signed that.
>> Yeah, I think I signed I think I
remember sign.
>> This is the group that's doing the all
the
testing. Yeah, they're going to test to
make sure their their number one concern
was the soil because it's so rocky. They
weren't sure they
>> drill into the ground with the
>> the anchors anchors for the solar
panels.
>> Um, but it's part of the ranch that
nobody ever sees or goes to and
graze on it. But other than that, we're
not maximizing the dollar value. So, uh,
finally, we've got somebody that's
really interested to have had some
input, uh, some requests. It's very
early. I don't know what ever happened,
but on the northwest
corner of the ranch, there are four
major gas lines that there
big gas lines.
There's been some interest in building a
natural gas fire power plant.
Um it's so early so early that it's
hardly worth talking about but
potentially that could be that could be
a revenue situation based as well.
Yes. And then existing next era um that
have that have the wind they were
interested in 25
maybe 50 acres. uh they would like to
build a battery storage facility so that
when they can't put it all in the line
they store it and then
I haven't heard anything recently
>> so like warehouse
>> no it's industrial batteries so they
when electricity is cheap they would put
the electricity charge the batteries and
when electricity is more expensive they
would sell electricity so they'd be
lithium ion
industrial scale lithium and battery.
>> What about the Greek company?
>> Have you heard from the public? No.
>> Have you? No. They were interested in
the metal period.
Last time we talked to the gentleman, he
was heading off for his honey. Never
heard from the guy. Someone else has.
So, I don't know if he ever got back or
not.
I need to follow with him.
So that's that's kind of the status
right now, but there actually is some
progress. So that's that's exciting.
>> I did have one question um
brave about the uh 15th Street Rail
Experience. We only have three of the
cars down here. There's still the fourth
car sitting out on the Swan Ranch. Is
that correct?
>> I think it was It's not I don't think
that
That was the one that just they tore it
totally apart.
>> Oh, they tore them all apart.
>> We're all mine.
>> But there was still the one that was
out. My understanding was there was
still going to be one out there that we
were either going to have to have
somehow get rid of and then we needed to
mitigate all of the soil um for the
little rail company that owns that
property.
And Tom had said it was like one and a
half inches deep all across that area
where there may have been asbestous
contamination.
I'm not sure.
>> I think that's accurate.
I don't know where we're at process.
>> Well, the reason I'm asking is because
that my understanding is that um they
were they had allowed us to keep it
there. The property changed hands after
we signed the lease or the agreement
with the previous owners to store those
out there. And so they had agreed to let
us continue on at no charge for a
certain amount of time, but I believe
that time is coming up. And so and they
are also bidding on some bigger projects
is what they the gentleman had told us
where they might be a staging area for
wind turbines. And so they're going to
need that space. So we're I mean I'm
just wondering what are we doing with
that fourth car?
>> That'd be a director question.
I'm I'm texting Mike right now as Matt.
>> Thank you for bringing that up. I'm not
familiar with it.
So, do we have any idea what the
gunslingers [snorts]
are going to do? What do they want to
do? They're going to be located
west. They're going to move west. It's
my understanding. That's not right.
Mayor
>> 7%. That's my understanding.
>> Yeah. Next for next year as part of the
15 rebuild.
>> We talk about house 2, what the plan is
now that it's been worked out. We're
gonna be able to
>> Any more any more questions on 15th?
Larry, if you get a response,
>> sure.
>> Did we ever get the report back
>> of what happened? of well not what
happened but if it's if the sky is
stable and so the uh you went out there
with the uh structural engineering team
and they feel like the walls themselves
are structurally still sound. Um the
challenge is going to be they have to
get a roof on it before winter because
if you get [clears throat] heavy snow on
there if if the roof comes down it could
take the walls out though uh Jason's
team is working on RP to get the old
roof removed to get better on it. If you
notice there's the stone walls and
there's some brick on the top. Some of
that brick has been damaged. Um, you
know, the water hit it, washed out the
the mortar and things like that. But
those bricks can be re reused and u and
restored. But overall, they thought the
building still structural and sound and
uh they project it'll cost a couple
hundred,000 more because of the damage,
but
the key is we've got to get a roof on it
before before
>> and it wasn't insured, right, at all.
And I'm sure
>> and that roof was going to have to be
completely replaced anyway.
>> Yeah. I But even I mean I don't even
though they arrested someone in that
case whether we would ever see any
>> that's
the problem is the position that's in
getting it off of there without it
collapsing the walls. So that's that's
going to be a challenge.
So something before
we should be expecting
should have something uh to do the work
to replace that.
>> Sounds like he'll got several projects
that could be quite a bit of money that
he didn't necessarily budget for like
the cost
>> that was part of the $4 million. So 4.2
2.13
>> and that's not enough to finish the job,
you think?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, I think so.
>> Waiting for TDSI to finish the build
building documents or the new the new
design.
Then we can finish once in the building
secured, we'll be able to finish.
I'm excited. We're not tearing down a
whatever it is named the D2 building
whatever it is they still want to be
told talked about remember doing that
other project you'd like an update on
>> other one is uh traffic violations and
road safety the only other one on the
list
>> that one um I think we continue to make
progress on that I think and councilor
was certainly instrumental in that the
safety Streets for All that came out. We
got we had that work session on with the
MO a couple of months ago and then the
work that Mr. Aean and Mr. Cobb have
done to really kind of try and update
how we look at crosswalks safety
recognizing the fact that some things
that we've been doing in the past are
somewhat archaic and really don't um
meet today's needs. Um, and so I think I
think we continue to make progress
there.
>> And we've made a lot of pulled a lot of
cars over, wrote a lot of tickets, and
there's new bond schedule. I think I
shared with you guys the new bond
schedule. Um, like you're 20 miles an
hour over
speed was $125 now 500 bucks.
>> So, wow. the new bond schedule from the
judge. He took our complaints about
speeding seriously and they jacked up
the cost of a speeding ticket. So, I'm
just telling you up to six miles an
hour, 5 miles an hour didn't change.
Once you hit six miles an hour, it goes
from like a 100 bucks to like $400.
>> So, and that just went into effect.
Do do you guys do this resolution to WAM
to uh allow to request the legislature
to allow cities and towns to reduce
urban speed limits?
>> We're not doing resolutions anymore.
>> Well, I know it's on here though. I
mean, did they did you bring it up at WH
or send it to WH? Anybody?
>> I didn't.
>> But it's on it's on our list to talk
about in the future.
Anywhere
>> at
>> Yeah. And we're talking about maybe
doing just for first class six
start so that we we can have the
authority to change our speed limits
without having to go through all the
time instead because now reality want to
change your uh speed liy
that so if we want to change in all our
neighborhoods we have to do traffic for
every mile. So why would you only want
that to be in the larger cities because
in small communities they don't have the
funding to be able to do traffic studies
to change theirs. The the thought is
that um it's probably not going to shoot
small. They got small because unless it
is
first class
>> I well
>> maybe
I'm talking about Alvin and Upton
>> like in L there's I mean that would be
something that even confused unless
>> we have talked about it hasn't had a lot
of a lot of traction.
[clears throat]
>> What about the critical traffic thing? I
I have had several residents who have
done their little petitions and things
and I think they're frustrated that
they, you know, they don't come up on
the the
cycle um as quickly as that what they
would like or at all because we've spent
as much time on the major.
>> I don't know if that's true. Um we've
had about maybe 10 or 12 petitions so
far, but we've gone out and studied them
and they come back. They're not a
problem. The one on dimming is the one
I'm thinking of where the residents keep
asking.
>> Yeah. Has it been addressed?
>> I think we did the study and allergy
85th
speed came out at 28 miles an hour and
speed limit 30. The perception people
have of speeding. It's just not reality.
Most of the ones we studied um speed
limit 30 and 85% or more of the cars are
going bad speed limit are slower and
there is no there is no need for
additional traffic because people are
obeying the law.
>> And has it got better on warrant finally
or no? Um, I don't think Warren's where
we want it to be. We're gonna we're
going to strike Warren or we're going to
strike Central Avenue um sometime here
in the next month or so uh to make two
11 foot lengths and the idea is that by
constricting the length it will slow
people down to see if that will work and
if it does we might do an avenue. So, we
got permission. Why not study? Um, but
yeah, looked at that. We had like the 10
or 12. The only one that's very active
right now, um, there's two that are
active that we're studying is uh, Bridge
Road, the new school year. We're waiting
for um during the school year. It
doesn't make sense to do it in summer.
There's no kids who want to understand
what the what the time is during school.
And there's a there's another situation
similar to that and I can't remember
which school it is where it got and
we're waiting to do that. We did mal
was one that I think did and 83% out 30
miles.
>> What was the average speed of the golf
ball on that wall?
>> Yes.
>> If I was hitting it not very fast. Are
we doing when when we review those and
then we don't
and we because of whatever reason we're
not going to consider that a critical
neighborhood. Do we send something out
to the people that have signed the
petition or the person who initiated it
so at least there's some sort of
response or feedback?
>> I'm sure Tom or Rick are doing that but
I could ask.
>> Okay. Because if they are these people
haven't don't seem to have received
anything. So
>> we we we we look at uh urban SDK. You
can look real quickly, see what it's
looking like, and then we put out the uh
the boxes and that takes a few weeks or
months, right, to to get a study to
figure out what what the actual
situation is. Uh and then based on that,
then we would make a decision whether it
qualifies. And I'm telling you guys,
>> it is amazing. Cars are going so fast
when we study it for a month. And
>> cars are going 28 miles an hour and 30 m
hours on the road. Thank you. Thank you.
But I think just making sure that we're
following up on it would be really
helpful.
>> A ridge there, changing the access into
the school.
>> Yeah.
>> So that may have a big difference with
that because now they'll turn there,
right?
>> Is it going to be like a circle bus
on Jackson?
>> Yeah. Instead of on Bridge Road.
>> The other thing is is that that school
doesn't really have kids that walk,
>> right? you know, there's very almost no
kids that walk. So, you know, needing a
school zone there, we've looked at
pedestrians, there aren't any. Yeah. And
so, we don't think that it requires
that. Although parents, we have school
districts or school zones everywhere
else. Yeah. Kids walk to their
neighborhood school. There's no you're
not a neighborhood school. You're a a
commuter school. And uh people are bus.
So, we definitely spend a lot of time
looking at those. I can see the school
from my backyard or from my window and
watching them after school and before
school. You never see kids cross your
red.
>> But as they're getting ready to go in
high school, they're going to get that
far.
>> Yeah,
I have a terrific question.
We approved bid to do all of the
say the name of it, but all the
crosswalks
>> the plastic
>> dermal plastic. Yeah, I haven't seen a
lot of that done yet.
>> Tom talked about it at the senior center
>> and he he just said that they're doing
that. Um but he didn't give a time frame
being back with the white dot project
and whatever white contractor does that
they'll do ours
money. I don't know what budgets be done
this fall yet, but I don't know exactly.
We also talked about that like on you
know um Yellowstone where certainly
range that all of that will be done but
they're not going to do anything until
they redo that intersection and stuff
because there's no point doing tearing
it up. I was just like from the schools
always.
I know they're going to do uh the the
pavement on
range from where they ended to the stop
line
will finally have their water line. We
didn't want to do that before the water
lines stopped. So we'll pave that and
then when we do the wind uh Yellowstone
del Range intersection that'll pick up
the last that
won't screw that one up. You don't want
to do an overlay and then have BOP come
in and out of the water line. So,
u
one other question, Mr. President, uh
[clears throat] the um parking lot that
we bought on 16th Street and the the
building behind it, where do we stand
on that? The one that's right above pump
house.
>> Oh, the little dealership.
>> Yeah, I forgot. They're they're in
there.
>> Oh, are they?
>> Yeah, they're in there working. I found
out the toilets being they build the
toilet with a hose. So, that's how they
were doing it back then. So, we we're
going to have to spend some money to
bring that to but it's working. They got
they got their equipment.
Great. Heard that.
>> I just heard I just heard that this
morning at our staff.
>> Great.
>> And if we do the municipal building, the
public
one, you may have heard about it as
we're on over on 21st in Ames and where
Eric got this giant pile of debris and
and uh cleaned it there.
>> Got it. Cleaned it. got it all cleaned
up by James Nation joined the land owner
actually. So we we had to
[clears throat]
with a couple of very happy land ownersh
were right around there after that got
done.
>> I am shocked guys when you go see the
pictures of some properties.
>> I just can't imagine.
So there was somebody living there or
>> No, there are two abandoned houses
there, but they were the landowner was
using this as a temporary dump ground
and build a giant pile of dirt there. Uh
and Ron Sorgan and Rain Luke was right
across the street had been after us for
a while and Eric jumped into it. Got it
done.
Great place.
>> Yeah.
I have one more project that's not on
our list that maybe you can give us an
update.
And the reason I'm asking this because I
walked by last week get into the pancake
breakfast bag was the hole in the hinds
supposed to start this fall.
>> Question.
>> I saw uh Amy Serdam at the uh
>> Frontier Days art show and she said they
are waiting for some contracts to be
signed but that they are still uh full
steam ahead.
>> The one the one big contract needs is
signed. So they've got all that stuff
done. So I I think the last hurdles have
been have been overcome now.
>> And I asked her about the building next
to
uh Greers old Greers furniture the Bell
building and she said that they are not
going to do parking now um except on the
main floor and then turn the rest of it
into locks because it just wasn't
feasible. like we could we all could do
that probably
you know when she was gonna do the
automated car lifting thing we all
looked at her
>> right
>> what
>> so but we said they're budget
>> I love what they did with the facade you
know the windows and stuff looks good
they're going to have to make that
building
>> um and I don't know u
is that good Tom
>> okay
>> thank you
>> uh one thing I wanted to bring up while
we're at it is I don't know if any of
you saw the story on channel 5 with
Peaches Terrell who's president of the
Mory Brown Foundation and the community
center project, but they've done all the
studies
um and and they have a bid out
>> to uh do the building demolition and
raising of the outlaw
>> and they've been meeting with the data
centers.
>> Yeah,
>> they have a sign there that says future
home.
>> Yeah, they just have sign. We have
exciting news and more.
>> They hope that's done. They they hope
that's done in two years.
>> The building
>> the whole project.
>> Last I heard it was over $100 million.
It's going to take that entire way to
the permits. So, um, in war three, we
have exciting news. When Chimney's Motel
got a fence put up around it and the
great big dumpster moved in, it's going
to be torn down.
>> Really going to be a newation
right now.
>> Another coffee shop.
>> Another coffee shop. We're also getting
a Dunkin Donuts.
>> Dunkin Donuts in war three. Yeah.
>> Dunkin.
>> Yeah. Where the old gas station was
really
>> and a new bank. A new bank.
>> Another corner. Midian trust is going on
the corner of where the old Wonderbread
store was.
>> Apparently someone didn't really like
seeing that happen though because I got
tagged on that corner.
I thought they put up some pretty funny
signs like, "Well, you should be
thankful it's not another car wash or
coffee."
>> Oh, on the twin chimney corner.
>> Oh, oh, yeah. Twin chimneys. Yeah, it'll
be good when
I'm a choir boy like me.
>> That's it. Been a long time coming.
There was a lot of
>> sad about the bread.
>> Both.
>> Yeah, both.
>> There was a lot of what I was
>> that were sad. We're reminiscing about
we called it the used bread store. My
>> kids call it that too.
We always called it the wonderful.
>> Yeah. How did my kids always call that?
>> My mom bought all of our bread when I
was growing up.
>> Same here.
>> And all of our little the pies for your
lunch box.
>> Yep.
Mr. President, you have you have
successfully discussed all of your goals
and and updated and I'm I'm really proud
of all of you for the accomplishments
you've made. Um, and and if I may, I I
don't know how how much you all get to
speak to people from outside of the area
during Frontier Days, but you know, as a
transplant, I guess, you know, and and a
talker. I'm a talker. Uh the the
compliments of outsiders to this city
are are astounding at how complimentary
they are of not not just Frontier Days.
I mean that that's all wonderful, but of
the city and that's because of all of
the work that you all do. So, I I hope
that you get to feel that during that
special time that that we during those
10 days
>> that we triple the population and and I
know we're all very tired, but but
they're complimentary of the city of
Shahid. And so, I I hope you're all very
proud of the work that you do because it
it it really makes this a very special
place.
>> You know, the comment I hear a lot that
always surprised me is how clean our
city is. They come from other places. I
can't think about Queen Cheyenne. I look
around and think okay
>> oh that's
>> but compared to other places
>> yeah I was say people who don't think it
is haven't traveled
>> but but downtown safe crew they
>> they are amazing
>> like I said those guys were out there at
3:00 a.m.
before that pancake breakfast.
>> But you were there before.
>> They were already an hour in.
>> But you know,
>> when I was helping those guys,
>> Jeff, I see his crew because a lot of
times I go in, if I go into the office,
I go in like 5:30 or 6:00 in the morning
and they are always already out on the
streets a year round. It's not just
Frontier Day.
>> So, I hope you all take the time to
celebrate the accomplishments that that
you've done. You know, I know I know you
all put feet up quite a bit for some
things, but but you do some really
amazing things and so be sure to
celebrate those accomplishments that
that you're doing to make a difference
to as a registered voter. I am saying
thank you to all of you.
>> Thank you for voting.
>> Yes. You know, that being said, there
still are some underlying conditions in
this city that we still need to take
care of. It's areas that the tourists
don't get to see, but that's very true.
>> Thank you all so much for being here.
>> I had a card and a small gift for your
effort.
Did you do any
>> Friday morning?
Friday morning.
>> Okay, good.
>> We're gonna do a quick tour of the golf
course. Go ahead.
>> Do you want me to
do We're all
>> Thank you. Thanks everybody.
>> Yeah. Do we need to tell you if we're
doing the
>> golf
forum